# Sergii Mavrov

Aachen, North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany



serg.mavrov@gmail.com



+4915733699427



linkedin.com/in/sergii-mavrov

# Summary

Over 18 years on all levels of IT. About 15 years as a Senior/Lead Java Developer/Architect in a few projects. I am a good team player, but there is no problem to work independently. I have experience with people management and able to work under pressure from the customers, experienced communicating with clients on all levels. My focus is on high-load applications, application security, performance analysis and optimization, but I can do any software engineering work while it makes sense.

#### Main technical areas:

Languages - Java, Scala

Technologies - J2SE, J2EE (Multi-Threading, CDI, JPA, Hibernate, Spring, Quarkus), SQL (Oracle, MySQL, Postgres), Docker, Kubernetes

Web - JavaScript, HTML, XML, Json Operating Systems - Windows, Linux

# **Experience**

# **Senior Java Developer**

Amadeus Leisure IT GmbH

May 2018 - Present (2 years 6 months +)
Project: Central Configuration Database

The group of projects and databases which are the infrastructure of the company: all dictionary (geo, price, etc.) information, an import-export data, etc.

#### Responsibilities:

- Work on requirements, understand and resolve dependencies
- Worked as part and the key player of the Agile team reviewing detailed design and key technical areas
- Implementing the key functionality
- Investigation and applying any tools/libraries
- Configuring and support all DEV and STAGING environment via DevOPS
- Performance and Stress testing
- Code review and mentoring

Technologies: J2EE, REST, SOAP, CDI, Weld, Tomcat, JPA, Hibernate, MySQL, MariaDB, SQL, MongoDB, Maven, SpringBoot, Microservices, Java 11, Docker, Kubernetes, PHP, Angular, JavaScript, Nginx

## **Senior Java Developer**

Amadeus Leisure IT GmbH

Jan 2014 - Apr 2018 (4 years 4 months)

Project: Dynamix Config Packaging Tool v2.0 in Traveltainment

The application is an important part of the Amadeus Company ecosystem. The system will be used to configure the search result from the global travel distribution system (flight tickets, hotel booking) depending on the business goals of b2b partners. The web application provides for travel operators agile ability to configure their systems and to provide the product maximally close to the client's wishes. The application works under very high loading and must provide very fast reaction for big size data.

#### Responsibilities:

- Work on requirements, understand and resolve dependencies from the first idea
- Worked as part and the key player of the Agile team reviewing detailed design and key technical areas
- Implementing the key functionality
- Investigation and applying any tools/libraries
- Configuring and support all DEV and STAGING environment via DevOPS
- Performance and Stress testing
- Code review and mentoring
- Communication and support QA and FE teams

Technologies: J2EE, Multi-Threading, REST, SOAP, CDI, Weld, Tomcat, Wildfly 8.2-10, JMS, JPA, Hibernate, MySQL, MariaDB, Galera, SQL, Maven

# Senior Java Developer

GlobalLogic

Mar 2013 - Mar 2014 (1 year 1 month)

The Vast project.

Vast is the premier provider of big data solutions for life's biggest purchases. Vast's industry-leading big data platform and applications are currently in use at many of the largest automotive, real estate and travel businesses in the world. Vast clients include AOL, Southwest Airlines and USAA.

The main project is Agent Portal. The web application is being used for organisation links between possible clients, brokers and real estate agents.

#### Responsibilities:

- Work on requirements, understand and resolve dependencies
- Worked as part of the team reviewing detailed design and key technical areas

Technologies: J2EE, Scala, Guice, Spray, REST web-services, Maven, Git

# C Senior Java Developer

Ciklum

Nov 2012 - Mar 2013 (5 months)

Project: Teamonline - Bosted/Incorp

The Bosted System is an IT solution for providers helping people with developmental disabilities. Bosted is the Danish word for 'residential homes'. Providing temporary use of on-line non-downloadable software for collecting, monitoring and analyzing data indicative of the health or condition of an individual for treatment and diagnostic purposes

Responsibilities:

- Work on requirements, understand and resolve dependencies
- Code review
- Worked as part of the team reviewing detailed design and key technical areas

Technologies: J2EE, Tomcat, Spring MVC, JSP, JavaScript, SQL, Ant, Maven, JUnit, Eclipse, SVN, Agile



# os Senior Java Developer 🚜

Lohika

Aug 2009 - Sep 2012 (3 years 2 months) HP Contractor, see below.



# Senior Java Developer, Activity Leader

Aug 2009 - Sep 2012 (3 years 2 months)

Activity leader of an R&D team working for HP (HP SiteScope CPE & Content Team, BSM Core2 Team)

HP SiteScope is an agentless monitoring solution designed to ensure the availability and performance of distributed IT infrastructures — for example, servers, operating systems, network devices, network services, applications, and application components. Quickly collect server and application health across physical, virtual and cloud infrastructures - including HP Cloud Services. SiteScope provides a simple yet powerful way to monitor a broad set of different technologies. This Web-based infrastructure monitoring solution is lightweight, highly customizable, and does not require that data collection agents be installed on your production systems. SiteScope empowers users to automate monitoring for today's dynamic cloud environments via APIs.

#### **Environment:**

 - J2SE, Multi-Threading, Memory management/memory optimization/fragmentation, Swing, Spring (IoC), JavaScript, SQL(Oracle), JMS, JMX, Ant, Maven, JProfiler, JUnit, QC, Eclipse, SVN, Agile

# Responsibilities & achievements:

- lead CPE process within a team
- Team is owning the development/enhancement/support of all the SiteScope monitors (120 monitors) feature development, new monitor development, integration with other HP products & Cloud solutions
- Help in recruitment and training new members of the team
- Work on requirements, understand and resolve dependencies
- Task related to CPE assigning, manage priorities, manage risks
- CPE result tracking, issues and scope changes
- Code review
- Worked as part of the team reviewing detailed design and key technical areas
- Direct communication with SiteScope customers



## Senior Java Developer, Architect

Qmeety Inc., Israel Oct 2011 - Aug 2012 (11 months) Qmeety is full-hosted service, which provides live chat solution for mini-sites within site groups. The application can be introduced to any customers site and provides the service of dialog for visitor-to-visitor, visitor-to-group.

#### Responsibilities:

- Work on requirements, understand and resolve dependencies
- Task related with planning, design, manage priorities, manage risks
- Implementation back-end of the application based on web-services

Technologies: J2EE, JBoss, Hibernate, SOAP, Rest, SQL(postgres), Ant, Maven, Eclipse, SVN, Agile



# Java Developer

#### Comodo

2008 - 2009 (2 years)

Projects:

Comodo's Two Factor Authentication Solution.

The project is authorized service for signing of private clients to secure Internet resources. The most popular solution is protection for online management system of bank accounts. The application checks the online user authentication and registers all users activity on the site in real time mode and blocks all unsecure actions. The solution is transparent for users, it looks like a part of the main system.

Certificate Manager for Secure SSL Certificate Administration.

The project is the service to enroll and control of states of certificates for large customers. The application is an intermediary between Comodo company and customer's management to provide the necessary ordering information. The service interacts with the Comodo auth center server for ordering and maintenance of certificates on the basis of the customer's arrangements.

#### Responsibilities:

- New features development
- Bugs fixing
- Work on requirements, understand and resolve dependencies, reviewing detailed design and key technical areas
- Code review
- Help in recruitment and training new members of the team

Technologies: J2SE, J2EE, GWT, JSP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL(MySQL), Ant, JUnit, Idea, SVN, Agile.



## Software Developer, Activity leader

#### Customs Transnistria

Sep 2005 - Aug 2008 (3 years)

Projects:

Few large and medium projects related to customs clearance (the main application related with the area was in my full responsibility), staff service, accounting, etc. They were created as "thick" Delphi clients + (DB stored procedures + triggers).

Technologies: Delphi, SQL(MS SQL), Foxpro, DBF, SVN.

New system based on J2EE should be replaced all previous projects. Many parts of the system have been created and integrated with old systems. The system was designed as few WEB applications with one authentication center for officers and clients.

Technologies: J2EE, Applets, JavaScript, JSF, EJB, Hibernate, SQL(MS SQL), JBoss, GlassFish, Netbeans, SVN, Agile.

## Responsibilities:

- Main designing
- New features development
- Bugs fixing
- Work on requirements, understand and resolve dependencies, reviewing detailed design and key technical areas
- Code review
- Help in recruitment and training new members of the team



# R&D manager

#### Tirotex

Jun 2004 - Aug 2005 (1 year 3 months)

I coordinated several teams responsible to support the IT environment of the factory. The main tasks were:

- The introduction of a new ERP system "Tirotex Max";
- The integration of data from the old existing systems to new "Tirotex Max" based on SOA architecture using any possible protocols;
- The development systems based on the two or three-tier applications (Delphi, FoxPro, Informix DB) in places where it was impossible to implement "Tirotex Max" way.

MAX+ is an integrated business management system intended for manufacturing, commercial and service companies. The main purpose of this system is to provide the whole range of IT services required for production, sales, procurement and finance management in compliance with strategy, policy and relationship between different business units of the enterprise.

While integrating enhanced capabilities in a basic product, MAX+ combines wide functionality with low cost of ownership and enables to easily upgrade the system that makes MAX+ an ideal ERP solution for both small and larger companies.

MAX+ System is designed for fast implementation, and supports different types of production including 'make to contract', 'make to order', 'make to store' and 'assemble to order'. The modular structure of the system, advanced and high-performance development tools, and the interfaces compliant with industry standards make it possible to flexibly adapt the system to fit the business processes of a company as well as to expand and upgrade the system as the company business grows.

#### Responsibilities:

- Coordination teams of developers for fast integration the new system
- Work on requirements, understand and resolve dependencies
- Searching ways to combinated old information system with new one
- Searching ways to optimize the people managment
- Help in recruitment and training new members of the team

- Worked as part of the team reviewing detailed design and key technical areas

# Software Developer, Activity leader

Tirotex

Aug 2002 - May 2004 (1 year 10 months)

Tirotex is the largest textile company in the southeast of CIS. It is a unique production complex with a strong infrastructure, advanced technical, organizational and scientific basis. It is an export sales oriented company. The volume of export deliveries is about 70% of the whole sales volume. The products of Tirotex are exported to 30 countries all over the world.

I have been involved as software developer in many places critical important to main processes. We were forced to change old data system based on MS DOS and Foxpro to new created oriented to more comfortable Windows design and modern data base servers. I was able to make the main process of the production and the control much more faster, simplest and cheapest in places which have been in my responsibility.

The main goal was step-by-step migration to new data system. It is an infomedia called "Tirotex MAX" combining all into one line: fiscal accounting, economic process of sale, production, materials management, support of all kinds of production.

Technologies: Foxpro, DBF, Delphi, Informix, MS SQL.

Responsibilities:

- New features development
- Bugs fixing
- Work on requirements, understand and resolve dependencies, reviewing detailed design and key technical areas

# **Education**



Lizenziat, mathematics, computer science

1997 - 2002



# School #12, Tiraspol, Moldova

physics, mathematics 1986 - 1996

# **Skills**

Spring Boot • JPA • REST • Agile Methodologies • OOP • Multithreading • Web Applications • Web Services • Design Patterns • SOA